# Alexander Rathke

Phone number: +353 85 848 3531 Email: <a href="mailto:rathkealex@gmail.com">rathkealex@gmail.com</a>
LinkedIn: <a href="https://bit.ly/3o1m6Tq">https://bit.ly/3o1m6Tq</a>

City: Dublin, Ireland

A motivated & energetic professional analyst working in elite performance environments. Analytically minded with a high level of initiative, organisation and comprehensive communication skills. Holds the ability to produce high-quality reports, visualisations under pressure and experience in numerous industries.

#### **Education**

MSc (Hons) Sports Performance / University of Limerick - 2016

Thesis: 'An examination of Expected Goals and Shot Efficiency in Soccer'.

#### BSc (Hons) Sports Management / University of College Dublin - 2014

Thesis: 'Factors influencing coach burnout in Irish elite sports coaches'.

# **Experience**

SEPTEMBER 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2022

#### People Data Analyst - Intercom - Dublin, Ireland

- Ensured Diversity Ethnicity & Inclusion (DEI) data collection strategies for new joiners
- Developed and managed DEI quarterly and annual reports for Executives and Leaders
- Collaborated on monthly reports Headcount, Attrition, Starts & Terms (etc) for department heads
- Handled data requests from managers and colleagues
- Building of internal Tableau Online People Data database and visualisation dashboards

JUNE 2018 - AUGUST 2021

# Data Analyst - Aon (ACIA) - Dublin, Ireland

- Re-developed data manipulation processes from SQL Server to Alteryx & Trifacta
- Build Tableau dashboards for internal colleagues from different departments
- Accomplished with the team, the combination of 5 different data sources into one Tableau dashboard
- Collaborated with colleagues and managers on incoming data requests
- Assisted with Tableau training for internal colleagues
- Led an organisation wise Tableau monthly user group

JUNE 2019 – OCTOBER 2019

#### Data Analyst - Dundalk FC – Dublin, Ireland

- Part-time work in Dundalk's qualification pathway to European Champions & Europa League
- Analysed opposition team data trends for technical staff, highlighting potential playing strategies
- Developed Tableau dashboards to assist and educate coaching staff on understanding data
- Aided the Technical Director with player scouting and implementation of a data flow process
- Software tools used: Alteryx, Python & Tableau

#### JANUARY 2019 - AUGUST 2019

## Data Analyst - Brand Athlete Agency - London, UK

- Designed and developed a data flow process which ingested 3rd party data to build a recruitment system
- Compiled and wrote player analysis & recruitment reports to identify & recruit players
- Software tools used: Alteryx, Python & Tableau

#### SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2019 & JANUARY - MAY 2022

## **Performance & Data Analyst - Tipperary GAA**

- Part-time evening & weekend work with Tipperary Senior Footballers
- Assisted with match-day analysis of data collection and led data flow visualisation process
- Developed Tableau dashboards to assist, educate and visualise performance metrics for management staff
- Software tools used: Microsoft Excel, Python & Tableau

#### **SEPTEMBER 2017 - MAY 2018**

## Performance Analyst - Doha, Qatar - Remote

- Part-time evening & weekend work as a remote analyst
- Assisted Head Analyst with match-day analysis of data collection.
- Build a data flow visualisation process using Tableau
- Software tools used: Microsoft Excel & Tableau

#### MARCH 2016 - JUNE 2017

## TV Analyst - StarTimes - London, UK

- Football analytics talk show covering teams and player's from the German Football Bundesliga
- Assisted with script writing to cover content for episodes
- Collaborated on video footage & data sourcing to add insight for stories
- Assisted with post-production editing

#### MARCH 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2016

# Performance Analyst Intern - Houston Dynamo, Houston, USA

## **Skills**

TableauAlteryxSQLPython

● Trifacta ● Microsoft Office ● Streamlit ● AWS & Impala

(Excel/PowerPoint)

#### Other information

Hobbies: Outdoor adventures, Sports, Travelling, Racing, Coding, Data visualisation

**Publications:** MSc paper publication

**Certifications:** Tableau Desktop / Alteryx core / Trifacta / SQL certification / Python

**Languages:** English & German

**Fun Facts:** Cycled around Ireland solo bike-packing in 2020

Example work: https://tabsoft.co/3hM4cCY